Contact

annuv1810@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/japanese-language-expert (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

SAP FI

Sap

Japanese interpertation

Languages

English (Native or Bilingual)

Japanese (Full Professional)

Certifications

SAP Certified Application Associate
- SAP S/4HANA for Financial
Accounting Associates 2021

Japanese Language Proficiency Test - Level N2

Advance Level of Japanese Language

Annu Verma

Japanese language Expert | JLPT N2 certified Gurugram, Haryana, India

Summary

Japanese Bilingual Expert with JLPT N2 certification. Experienced as bilingual support across IT, E-commerce, Travel industry.

I believe in quality work and always put my level best efforts in achieving the high standards. I am competent enough to deliver more than expected and interactive enough to form a clique & better team environment.

Beside this I am a highly curious person always willing to learn new stuff and put myself to test.

Experience

Fujitsu

Delhi. India

Application Developer May 2022 - Present (1 year 1 month)

- translating SAP documents
- acting as an interpreter
- handling foreign correspondence
- meeting and greeting clients
- typing and compiling reports
- managing databases
- recruiting, training and supervising junior staff
- Read given material and research industry-specific terminology
- Cross-reference specialized dictionaries and translation tools to check quality of translation
- Follow up with internal team members and clients to ensure translation meets their needs
- Edit content with an eye toward maintaining its original format (e.g. font and structure)
- Network with field experts to stay current on new translation tools and practices

MITSUBISHI CORPORATION INDIA PRIVATE LIMITED

Bilingual Executive Assistant

May 2019 - May 2022 (3 years 1 month)

New Delhi, Delhi, India

:

- Communicating with Japanese clients and HQ in japan/ to create document according to MD.
- Admin work (prepare voucher, arrange invoice, communicating with vendors for monthly invoices and contracts)
- Accounting work- (expense booking in system, maintaining expense record excel file)
- Translation NNA newspaper and other Japanese documents.
- Maintaining monthly attendance sheet for staff.
- Support in statutory audit and internal audit.
- Support in monthly and annual closing to accounts team
- Schedule management for MD / booking hotel, cab, business trip settlement

ISFnet, Inc.

Information Technology Support Engineer February 2018 - March 2019 (1 year 2 months)

Japan

.

- Work of applying noise to multifunction devices.
- Work of measuring the time taken to pass through the paper.
- Work of applying static electricity to bolts and boards of multifunction devices.
- Assembling work of newly used multifunction machines and finishers.
- Work that performs USB direct print, color copy, built-in printing, etc.
- Work that passes paper in various modes such as specified paper type, size, number of sheets, etc. """

ANEW LINK LEARNING INDIA PRIVATE LIMITED

Manager, Japanese translator & interpreter And Assistant Teacher December 2014 - March 2017 (2 years 4 months)

Gurugram, Haryana, India

I am working here as a manager, translator, interpreter and lecturer.

I used to participated in the conference, Demo class and conversation with Japanese parents for enrolling their child and teaching Japanese students using KUNO METHOD.

In the KUNO Method, I instructed to use "ability to think", and lastly give them a written test to check their ability and performance.

Xroad Solutions Private limited 2 years 4 months

Bilingual Customer Service Representative November 2013 - November 2014 (1 year 1 month)

Gurugram, Haryana, India

Promoted as a branch manager and my work required to talk with Japanese customers, making bills and maintain all accounting activities. Other than that I am also involving to making & implementing strategies to increase sales and business.

Bilingual Customer Service Representative August 2012 - October 2013 (1 year 3 months) Gurugram, Haryana, India

I am working here as a translator and interpreter to solve the problems that occur with Japanese expats to their day to day life.

For example, FRRO, Pan Card etc. It is necessary procedure to follow to stay in India.

Education

Indira Gandhi National Open University Master of Arts - MA · (2017)

Delhi University
Bachelor of Arts - BA · (2011)

Central Board of Secondary Education Higher Secondary (2007)